DOAA SAAFAN

Dublin, Ohio

Email: <u>doaa_safan2000@yahoo.com</u>

Phone: 6149298196

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/doaa-saafan-32923b64/
Portfolio: https://doaasaafan.github.io/UX_UI_HW_19/

SUMMARY

UI/UX designer studied at Ohio State University UI/UX bootcamp program. Specializing in user research, usability testing, information architecture, wireframing, prototyping and interaction design, aim to create interfaces that are usable, enjoyable and accessible and that meet the needs of the user.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technical:

Google Suite Microsoft Office Trello Slack Zoom

UX/UI:

User Research
Information Architecture
Storyboarding / User Journey Mapping
Wireframing
Responsive Design
Usability Testing
Iterative Design Thinking
User Interface Prototyping
Heuristic Evaluation Testing

Web:

HTML / CSS Javascript Adobe XD / Sketch / Figma / Miro

Programming:

C/C++/Java Java Script PHP SQL DB2 Python

PROJECTS

Peer to Peer Mobile Application | Link to Project [always write out link address]

- Design a mobile application for self storage which helps anyone to rent out spaces he needs from someone near him or list unused space for rent and increase his income.
- Used Figma and Google suite.

US Department of Interior Desktop Application | Link to Project [always write out link address]

- Redesign the website of the US Department of Interior.
- Used Figma and Google suite.

Hope for children Desktop Application Link to Project [always write out link address]

- Redesign the website of Hope for Children, a non profit charity website which collects donations to aid sexually and physically abused children .
- Used Figma and Google suite.

EXPERIENCE

UX/UI Designer

May 2024- Sep 2024

The Ohio State University

Dublin,Ohio

"Hope for Children"

Redesign the website of Hope for Children, a non profit charity website which collects donations to aid sexually and physically abused children.

- "US Department of Interior Redesigning the website and desktop application.
 - "Peer to Peer"

 And the second results at the second results

Create a self storage mobile application.

System Administrator and Administration Supervisor Raya Information Technology	2012 - 2015 Cairo/Egypt
	Senior Customer Relation Administrator
Selliof Customer Relation Administrator	2009 - 2012
Raya Information Technology	Cairo/Egypt

EDUCATION

UI/UX Boot Camp Certificate: Ohio State of University

An intensive 24-week long boot camp.

Application Development Boot Camp: Ministry of Communication and Information Technology

An intensive 9 months long boot camp by IBM.

Certifications:

- UI/UX designer OSU
- Certified Associate in Project Management PMP
- Creative Problem Solving and Decision Making Raya Academy
- Quality Management System TUV
- IBM Certified Application Development with IBM WebSphere Studio
- IBM Certified Associate Developer WebSphere Studio
- IBM Certified Database Associate-DB2 Universal Database
- IBM Certified Solution Developer XML and Related Technologies
- Soft Skills
 Dale Carnegie
- Communication Skills
 Logic Management Consulting

B.A English language and literature: Ain Shams University - cairo Egypt